{
    "id": "d13578850e064e68b1cc583b6ad3aab2",
    "title": "General Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "We ………………………. each other since our school days.",
            "description": "We normally use the present perfect or past perfect tense with since.",
            "answers": [
                "know",
                "knew",
                "have known"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "They had been close friends since Janet …………………. small.",
            "description": "A past tense can be used in the since-clause depending upon the meaning.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "has been"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "In my opinion, too ………………………… mathematics is taught in schools.",
            "description": "The words mathematics, physics and politics are singular countable and have no plural forms. Hence we use much with them.",
            "answers": [
                "many",
                "much",
                "more"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Politics ………………………… a dirty game.",
            "description": "Politics is normally used as a singular uncountable noun.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are",
                "have"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The unemployment statistics …………………………. disturbing.",
            "description": "While statistics is usually singular, it does have a plural use.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Cattle …………………………… dying due to drought.",
            "description": "Cattle is a plural word and hence it takes a plural verb.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are",
                "was"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "They have a house on the ………………………… of the city.",
            "description": "Outskirts is usually plural and has no singular form. ",
            "answers": [
                "outskirt",
                "outskirts",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "They are raising ………………………….. for disadvantaged children.",
            "description": "Funds means money. ",
            "answers": [
                "fund",
                "funds"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "My …………………………. too tight.",
            "description": "The noun trousers is always used in the singular form.",
            "answers": [
                "trouser is",
                "trousers is",
                "trousers are"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If I were in that situation, I would scream until somebody …………………………. to help me.",
            "description": "Would and should are mainly used in main clauses. To express the same idea we use a past tense in the subordinate clauses.",
            "answers": [
                "comes",
                "would come",
                "came"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "A couple of my friends ……………………………. visiting us today.",
            "description": "Plural verbs are used after expressions like a couple of + plural noun.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Half of his students …………………………. understand his theories.",
            "description": "We use a plural verb after half of.",
            "answers": [
                "doesn't",
                "don't",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}